Hello, everyone.
大家好。
Let's start the 6th lecture.
让我们开始第六次讲座。
Today,
今天，
we are going to continue the inter process communication to talk
我们将继续进行进程间通信来交流。
about the inter process communication primitives.
关于进程间通信原语。
In particular,
特别是，
we are going to talk about sockets which allowed to applications
我们将讨论允许应用程序使用的套接字。
to communicate over the network.
进行网络通信。
And then we are going to start talking about concurrency.
然后我们将开始讨论并发性。
This will be a pretty long topic which will go over the pure next,
这将是一个相当长的话题，将详细介绍纯粹的下一个。
a couple of lectures.
几节课程。
As always, if you have any questions,
如常，如果你有任何问题，
please ask in the q and a thread,
请在问答主题中提问。
or i'll try also to check on the chat.
或者我也会尝试在聊天中查看。
Let's start.
让我们开始吧。
So,
那么，
again, like we discussed earlier in this class,
再次，就像我们在这堂课上讨论过的那样，
today, a lot of applications are distributed, right?
是的，现在有很多应用程序是分布式的，对吗？
They are not only running on a single machine on your laptop,
它们不仅在你的笔记本电脑上运行在单台机器上，
but most of them, they have a back end.
但是大多数情况下，它们都有一个后端。
You need to go over the network in order to implement
你需要通过网络来实现。
almost any functionality of the application.
几乎可以实现应用程序的任何功能。
And the exam, your web browser is a great examples.
而且考试中，你的网络浏览器是一个很好的例子。
Anything you are using today almost like many of the applications like facebook,
今天你使用的任何东西几乎都像许多应用程序一样，比如Facebook，
twitter,
Twitter是一个社交媒体平台，用户可以通过发布短消息（推文）与其他用户进行交流和分享信息。用户可以关注其他用户，以便在其发布新推文时收到通知。Twitter也被广泛用于实时新闻报道、舆论交流和社交网络营销。
and google application like google docs.
以及谷歌应用，如谷歌文档。
And obviously google itself as they look this way,
而且显然谷歌自己也是这个样子的，因为他们看起来就是这样的。
you have a piece of code running on the client side, on your machine,
你在客户端上有一段代码在你的机器上运行。
on your phone,
在你的手机上，
and a bigger piece of code which runs on the back end,
还有一个在后端运行的更大的代码片段，
on a bunch of servers in the data centers.
在数据中心的一堆服务器上。
And typically, all these applications, in general,
通常情况下，所有这些应用程序，总的来说，
looks like that, like this.
看起来是这样的，就像这样。
The client sends a request,
客户端发送一个请求，
and it gets a reply back.
然后它收到了一条回复。
The request can be a query and google.
该请求可以是一个查询和谷歌搜索。
The reply can be the answers to that.
回复可以是对那些问题的答案。
The it can be the reply to your search query.
这可能是对你搜索查询的回复。
And for something like that flicks,
对于这样的闪烁问题，
the reply will be,
回复将会是：
as a request will be your clicks.
作为请求，将是您的点击。
Selecting a movie,
选择一部电影，
the reply can be also recommendation of other movies or the movies
回复还可以是其他电影或电视剧的推荐。
start streaming and things like that.
开始流媒体和类似的事情。
And typically you have more than one client talking with the same set
通常情况下，您会有多个客户端与同一组进行通信。
about the same machine.
关于同一台机器。
And like, for instance,
例如，
have many web clients,
有很多网络客户端
and the many of them are talking with the same web server.
而且他们中的许多人都在与同一个网络服务器进行通信。
This is a kind of pattern communication pattern we have to implement
这是一种我们需要实现的通信模式。
under the hood.
在幕后。
So here it's about how also a little bit more and more details
这里是关于如何更详细地了解一些细节的内容。
about how client and the server are similar.
关于客户端和服务器的相似之处。
And even more importantly,
而且更重要的是，
how they are different.
它们有何不同之处。
The client again, sends a request,
客户端再次发送请求，
like get index html this basically specified to get as a content of the web
获取index.html文件，这基本上指定获取网页的内容。
page of a site of the first page of a site to render on your machine.
在您的计算机上渲染一个网站的第一页页面。
And in order to do that,
为了做到这一点，
you need to contact a server which stores the index dot html,
你需要联系一个存储 index.html 的服务器。
this fight, the content of the page you want to render on your machine.
这个问题是关于在你的机器上渲染页面的内容。
One thing obviously need to do is that when we need to know is the address
有一件明显需要做的事情是，当我们需要知道的是地址时。
of that server,
该服务器的
right?
对的？
It's like when you make a call,
就像你打电话时，
you need to know the number you are calling.
你需要知道你要拨打的号码。
Okay?
好的？
So keep in mind that.
请记住这一点。
So you need to know the address of the seller from it.
所以你需要从中得知卖家的地址。
You get the content.
你已经获得了内容。
And now the server,
现在是服务器的回合，
it's typically always on,
它通常是一直开启的。
it has always to be ready to receive requests and answer this request.
它必须始终准备好接收请求并回答这些请求。
Unlike on the other hand,
与另一方面不同的是，
obviously is a client.
显然是一个客户端。
It's not always on your phone, your computer,
它并不总是在你的手机、电脑上，
your laptop is not always on most of the time.
你的笔记本电脑并不总是开机，大部分时间都是关机的。
It's actually off.
它实际上是关闭的。
But when it's on, it's going to send his request to a server.
但是当它开启时，它会将请求发送到服务器。
We should be on all the time in order for you to get the reply right away.
我们应该始终保持在线，这样你就能立即收到回复。
And obviously,
显然，
the clients initiate the conduct of the server nor the other way around.
客户端发起服务器的行为，而不是反过来。
The client know doesn't need to know to have a because of that,
因此，客户端不需要知道有一个。
the client doesn't need to have a well known address,
客户端不需要拥有一个众所周知的地址，
but the server has to okay.
但是服务器必须正常运行。
And like we said before,
就像我们之前说的一样，
when the server gets a required as aa request,
当服务器收到一个名为"aa"的请求时，
it's going to answer something back,
它将会回答一些信息。
hopefully satisfying the reply,
希望这个回复能够令您满意，
answering the reply according to the user expectations.
根据用户的期望回复。
Again, we need to call to send data over the network.
再次，我们需要调用来发送数据通过网络。
And what we do that,
我们要做的是什么？
we need to send, we are going to send some bites.
我们需要发送一些数据，我们打算发送一些字节。
Data consists of bits.
数据由位组成。
We aggregate each eight beats.
我们将每八个节拍聚合在一起。
It's a one bike,
这是一辆自行车。
typically of majoring bytes,
通常是指主要的字节类型。
like memory.
像内存一样。
You also typically major in bytes,
你通常也会专攻字节。
or maybe which is a bunch of bytes.
或者说它是一串字节。
So more than that is not only we have individual bytes,
所以不仅仅是我们有单独的字节，
we have stream of bytes.
我们有一串字节流。
Remember, the stream of bytes is the same interface,
记住，字节流是相同的接口。
the high level interface from the file systems.
文件系统的高级接口。
Here, we are going to talk more about networking later in the lecture,
在这里，我们将在后面的讲座中更多地讨论网络。
but here we are talking about dcp connection.
但是在这里我们正在讨论DCP连接。
Tcp stands for transport control protocol.
TCP是传输控制协议的缩写。
Do you know what is the other type of protocol?
你知道还有哪种类型的协议吗？
Common protocol?
常见协议？
Besides dcp udp what does udp stands for?
除了数据复制协议（DCP）之外，UDP 还代表什么？
And icmp acdp is a protocol,
ICMP（Internet Control Message Protocol）和ACDP（Application Control and Data Plane）都是协议。
but a a it's at a higher level.
但是它是在更高的层次上。
It's on top of the tcp udp it's user data, ground protocol,
它位于TCP和UDP之上，是用户数据的底层协议。
not unified user data,
不统一的用户数据
ground protocol.
地面协议。
And http and ftp are also protocols,
HTTP和FTP也是协议。
but they are the higher levels they are running on top of pcp again,
但它们是在 PCP 上运行的更高级别的组件。
we are going to learn the network.
我们要学习网络。
Software is organizing stacks a in a bunch of players.
软件正在将一堆玩家的堆栈进行组织。
Here we are going to talk about the transport layer and pcp and udp are
在这里，我们将讨论传输层以及PCP和UDP。
传输层是计算机网络中的一层，负责在源主机和目标主机之间提供可靠的数据传输。它使用不同的协议来实现这一目标，其中包括传输控制协议（TCP）和用户数据报协议（UDP）。
PCP是端口控制协议（Port Control Protocol）的缩写，它是一种用于网络地址转换（NAT）设备的协议。PCP允许主机在私有网络中使用公共IP地址，并通过NAT设备与公共互联网通信。
UDP是用户数据报协议（User Datagram Protocol）的缩写，它是一种无连接的传输协议。与TCP不同，UDP不提供可靠的数据传输，也不保证数据的顺序。UDP通常用于实时应用程序，如音频和视频流传输，以及简单的请求-响应通信。
希望以上信息对你有帮助！如果你还有其他问题，请随时提问。
at the transport layer.
在传输层。
So thanks for your answers.
感谢您的回答。
So now we need to abstract the connection between two employees and b
现在我们需要对两个员工和b之间的连接进行抽象化处理。
the way we are going to do that,
我们打算这样做，
it should be, again, be very natural,
应该再次强调，非常自然。
because you are going to send a string of bytes.
因为你将要发送一个字节串。
You need to abstract like a cube,
你需要像一个立方体一样进行抽象化处理，
write yaq because,
写yaq的原因是，
for instance, aa very simple example,
例如，一个非常简单的例子，
what happened if the client sends faster than the server can receive
如果客户端发送的速度快于服务器接收的速度，会发生什么情况？
or the server,
或者服务器，
for some reason,
由于某种原因，
is doing something else.
正在做其他事情。
And you cannot get the data sent to it right away.
你不能立即获取发送给它的数据。
This data is either is lost,
这些数据可能已经丢失了，
or if you don't want to lose it,
或者如果你不想丢失它，
you need to buffer summer.
你需要缓冲夏天。
Right?
对吗？
So you have to have a cure, right?
所以你必须有一个解决办法，对吗？
You need to have boss on from the client to the servant,
你需要在客户端和服务端之间建立一个主从关系。
from the server to the client,
从服务器到客户端，
because both of them, they are going to send data.
因为它们都要发送数据。
One of them is going to send typically request,
其中一个将发送典型的请求。
and the other one replies to the request.
另一个回复该请求。
Now,
现在，
but what is the abstraction?
但是什么是抽象化？
Right?
对吗？
This is kind of,
这有点...
how do we manipulate this kind of connection?
我们如何操作这种连接？
And remember that one of the big things about unix is that everything looks
而且请记住，Unix的一个重要特点就是一切看起来都是
like a file,
像一个文件一样，
right?
对的？
Or it's abstract with very similar abstractions.
或者它是抽象的，具有非常相似的抽象概念。
The same is true for communication,
通信也是如此。
like we saw for pipes.
就像我们在管道中看到的那样。
Last time.
上次。
Pipes.
管道。
Again, it's how you communicate between two processes on the same machine.
再次强调，它是关于如何在同一台机器上的两个进程之间进行通信的。
Here are sockets about how you come,
这里是关于你如何连接的套接字的信息。
how do two processes on different machines communicate with each other.
两台不同机器上的两个进程如何进行通信？
But they are very similar that the abstraction is very similar,
但它们非常相似，抽象概念非常相似。
and is looking like a fire.
看起来像是一场火灾。
And this kind of abstraction for communication is called a socket.
这种用于通信的抽象称为套接字。
This is how you do it.
这是你要做的方法。
Right?
对吗？
If you want to send some data,
如果你想发送一些数据，
the processor sender is a client call or write system function call,
处理器发送者是一个客户端调用或写系统函数调用。
which passes a descriptor.
传递一个描述符。
This is a soccer descriptor,
这是一个关于足球的描述符。
a buffer in the length of the buffer.
一个长度为缓冲区大小的缓冲区。
And the receiver or the server.
接收方或服务器。
It's calling the read operation with a file descriptor and aa
它正在使用文件描述符和 aa 调用读取操作。
buffer where it can receive the data on the size of the buffer.
缓冲区可以接收与缓冲区大小相匹配的数据。
To make sure that if it's more data,
为了确保如果有更多的数据，
the operating system doesn't overflow that buffer.
操作系统不会溢出该缓冲区。
Right?
对吗？
The circuits is the endpoint of communication, right?
电路是通信的终点，对吗？
And the cures are in between here somewhere along.
而治愈方法就在这里之间的某个地方。
Actually,
实际上，
there are many queues in the network that choosing
网络中有许多队列可供选择。
the operating system queues as the routers along the path
操作系统将排队作为路径上的路由器
between the sender and the receiver.
发送者和接收者之间的通信。
It's pretty complicated.
这很复杂。
We are going to learn more about that.
我们将会更多地了解这个。
But in general,
但是一般来说，
the things to for you to know that are accused, there are cues,
你需要知道的事情是被指控的事情，有线索。
one of the simplest reasons,
最简单的原因之一，
one of simple motivation for cures is to, again,
治愈的一个简单动机是，再次，
because the client or the two end points,
因为客户端或两个端点，
they don't have the same speed sending and receiving.
它们在发送和接收方面的速度不相同。
If you receive at a lower speed,
如果你以较低的速度接收到数据，
they need to buffer the data or that the receiver at that time,
他们需要对数据进行缓冲，或者在那个时候接收方需要进行缓冲。
maybe is doing something else.
可能正在做其他事情。
And he cannot receive the data right away.
他无法立即接收数据。
So now,
所以现在，
the circuits you have two sockets connected over the network,
这个电路有两个通过网络连接的插座。
one of the sender,
发送者之一
and on the receiver or one circuit for each endpoint.
在接收端，或者每个端点都需要一个电路。
Now,
现在，
the sockets, you remember,
套接字，你记得吧，
what do you do with sockets?
你可以用套接字做什么？
Right?
对吗？
It's like, what is a typical?
这就像是，什么是典型的？
What is a pattern?
什么是模式？
Programming pattern?
编程模式？
You open, you read,
你打开，你阅读，
if you have a file descriptor,
如果你有一个文件描述符，
like you open the file, a script,
就像你打开一个文件，一个脚本，
or you read right from the file, a script,
或者你可以直接从文件中读取，一个脚本，
and then you close the file list.
然后你关闭文件列表。
So we need to learn about how to open and close are also these sockets.
所以我们需要学习如何打开和关闭这些套接字。
Let me see,
让我看看，
here is a question is a communication between two processes,
这是一个关于两个进程之间通信的问题。
actually communication between the threat of the processes.
实际上是进程之间的通信。
This is, so anyone wants to answer that question?
这是，有人想回答这个问题吗？
The communication it's about is between two processes.
这里所讨论的通信是指两个进程之间的通信。
But remember, the process is a container.
但是要记住，进程是一个容器。
Right?
对吗？
You have the other place,
你有另一个地方。
other space,
其他空间
and it provides a protection.
它提供了一种保护机制。
But the actual unit of execution or concurrency is a thread.
但实际的执行单元或并发单元是线程。
Each thread, each process is at least one thread.
每个线程，每个进程至少有一个线程。
So it's correct to say that the processes communicate.
所以说进程之间进行通信是正确的。
But it's also say it's correct to say that always to stress communicate,
但也可以说，始终强调沟通是正确的。
because the things which are going to run the code inside this process are
因为将要运行此进程内代码的事物是
the threads.
线程。
Typically, when you have one thread and one process,
通常情况下，当你有一个线程和一个进程时，
you just interchangeable.
你只是可以互换的。
You can use process or thread,
你可以使用进程或线程。
but hopefully that answers the question.
但希望这回答了你的问题。
Okay?
好的？
It is a hidden abstraction for socket io what we are going to talk about here,
我们将在这里讨论的是socket io的隐藏抽象。
it's pretty much,
这差不多就是这样了。
at least in the next couple of slides about,
至少在接下来的几张幻灯片中，
actually, is how you are going to use a socket interface.
实际上，你将如何使用套接字接口。
Right?
对吗？
So
所以
like we discuss the circuit is an abstraction for on end point of the network.
就像我们讨论的那样，电路是网络的一个端点的抽象表示。
If you have do you have, in general,
如果你有的话，一般来说，
you have two processes to end points communicate with each other.
你有两个进程，它们之间进行通信。
Each of them is going to have a socket.
每个人都会有一个套接字。
And somehow you need to connect these two sockets to each other.
你需要以某种方式将这两个套接字连接起来。
If you want to establish a connection,
如果你想建立连接，
it was introduced first in berkeley standard distribution version 4.2.
它首次在伯克利标准发行版4.2中引入。
That is one of the biggest contributions
这是其中一个最大的贡献之一
of actually open source contribution of berkeley,
伯克利实际上的开源贡献
because has huge impact.
因为它有巨大的影响。
And the story here is that then the runners like during those days,
这里的故事是，在那些日子里，跑步者们就像这样，
you distribute these operating systems through tapes.
你通过磁带分发这些操作系统。
And the things here is that it's about how you are going to.
这里的关键是你将如何去做。
Then there are people waiting in line for the tapes to be copied.
然后还有人在排队等待磁带复制。
Therefore, to take it back to their companies,
因此，将其带回他们的公司，
to install the new version of unix,
安装新版本的Unix操作系统
to which with this kind of dcpipa code in it.
其中包含有这种类型的DCPIPA代码。
A this is a beautiful thing is that this is the local, again,
这是一件美好的事情，就是这个地方，再次，
it's like it's the abstraction for a lot of kind of networks,
它就像是许多种网络的抽象化。
not networks type of when I say a lot of kind of networks i'm talking about,
当我说到网络的不同类型时，我指的是很多种不同的网络。
all boss about how how they are physically implemented.
所有的老板都关心他们是如何在物理上实现的。
They are over fiber,
它们通过光纤传输。
they are over satellite cellular networks.
它们通过卫星蜂窝网络进行连接。
It abstracts away what kind of your application on your iphone.
它将您在iPhone上的应用程序的种类抽象化了。
It doesn't knew, it doesn't know that you are on a solar network, right?
它不知道，它不知道你在一个太阳能网络上，对吗？
Or you are a wifi, right?
或者你是一个无线网络，对吗？
Doesn't know.
不知道。
That means abstraction in that case.
在这种情况下，这意味着抽象化。
Or there are also about how packets are rooted in the network
还有关于数据包在网络中如何路由的内容。
and many other things.
还有许多其他事情。
Lower level of the network stack resource,
网络栈资源的较低层级
apple dog and ipx and the great thing about this tcpip it becomes an effect
苹果、狗和IPX，而TCP/IP的伟大之处在于它变得有效。
of standard of how
如何的标准
nodes communicate over the internet.
节点通过互联网进行通信。
Right?
对吗？
This is what enables the internet at the end of the day.
这就是最终使互联网成为可能的东西。
And again, when I say the vector standard,
再次强调，当我提到向量标准时，
I say because it doesn't,
我说它不是因为它不是这样的。
it was a piece of gold.
它是一块黄金。
It was not a standard body to create it,
没有一个标准的机构来创建它，
but it's a standard now because everyone is using it.
但现在它已成为标准，因为每个人都在使用它。
If you don't use the cpip you cannot talk with other as a noise in the internet.
如果你不使用CP/IP协议，你就无法在互联网上与其他人进行通信，就像在噪音中一样。
Okay?
好的？
The sockets,
套接字，
you'll see,
你会看到，
it's a little bit more elaborated interface.
这是一个稍微更加详细的界面。
But at the end of the day, you need to open,
但归根结底，你需要打开，
you need to create a socket.
你需要创建一个套接字。
You can close a socket in between you read and read and write.
在读取和写入之间，您可以关闭套接字。
Now,
现在，
Everything is a file descriptor,
一切皆为文件描述符。
like we discussed, but loss also, if you remember,
就像我们讨论过的那样，但也有损失，如果你还记得的话。
like we discussed,
正如我们讨论过的，
although you have every everything is file escaped out,
尽管你已经对所有内容进行了文件转义处理，
you don't have for each device.
你不需要为每个设备都有。
You don't have all the comments,
你没有所有的评论。
like you have four file systems, right?
你有四个文件系统，对吗？
For right?
是的，正确的。
For five system, you remember you have a sick, right?
对于五个系统，你记得你生病了，对吗？
You can reposition the pointer from what you read in a particular file.
你可以根据在特定文件中读取的内容重新定位指针位置。
I can lc and I can read from the 100 bytes in the file, right?
我可以使用 lc 命令来统计文件中的行数，并且可以从文件中读取100个字节，对吗？
Is still,
仍然是的，
the abstraction is still aa stream of bites, right?
抽象仍然是一串字节流，对吗？
But I can reposition.
但是我可以重新定位。
Here.
在这里。
You cannot have sick, right?
你不能生病，对吗？
You send up, have you send the bias and you receive that?
你发送了吗？你发送了偏置并且你收到了吗？
Or in the same order?
还是按照相同的顺序？
It is kind of strange to be out.
出门感觉有点奇怪。
I want to read the 100 bytes, right?
我想读取100个字节，对吗？
Maybe that 100 bytes is not even your computer haven't received it.
也许那100字节甚至都没有被你的计算机接收到。
So you don't have lc your abstraction is just a cube right?
所以你没有局部性，你的抽象只是一个立方体对吗？
In.
在。
First out,
首先，
you always get the but data in the order.
你总是按照顺序获取错误的数据。
And if you sent the other thing what happens is
如果你发送了其他的东西，会发生什么呢？
under the hood is abstracted away is that you don't over the network,
在抽象层下隐藏的是你不需要通过网络进行操作。
you don't send us small bikes, right?
你们不会给我们寄小型自行车，对吗？
You actually put it in packages in your package it.
你实际上将它放在你的包裹中打包。
You divide the data,
你将数据分割成不同的部分，
you have to send your package it in a pack.
你需要将你的包裹装在一个包装盒里。
Each packet will have addresses, right?
每个数据包都会有地址，对吗？
Because it depends on this tells another where is the packet should be delivered.
因为它取决于这个信息，告诉另一个设备数据包应该被传送到哪里。
Right?
对吗？
It's like you put amazon is using trucks and each truck now says an address,
就像你把亚马逊使用卡车的情况，每辆卡车现在都有一个地址。
the driver where it should deliver the packages.
司机应该将包裹送到哪里。
Right?
对吗？
Something like that.
差不多这样。
The many need also some kind of like rbc kind of facility to,
许多人也需要一种类似于红细胞（rbc）设施的东西。
for instance,
例如，
because the data format,
由于数据格式，
which is understand by the receiver,
能够被接收者理解的。
is not as the same as the data format,
不同于数据格式。
which is understood,
这是可以理解的，
understand by the senate.
被参议院理解。
Right?
对吗？
And you'll talk about this is big indian,
你将讨论这是大端序。
little indian kind of different formats,
小端（Little-endian）是一种不同的数据格式。
different for different processors.
对于不同的处理器来说是不同的。
This is a very simple example echo server.
这是一个非常简单的回显服务器示例。
Hello, world echo mean,
你好，"echo" 是指将输入的内容原样输出。
I am sending is a message to the server.
我正在发送一条消息给服务器。
The server is going to send me the message back.
服务器将会把消息发送回给我。
Right?
对吗？
So here is how things that are happening, right?
所以这就是正在发生的事情，对吗？
You have a client on the seller on the left hand side,
您在左侧有一个卖家客户端。
stubborn on the right hand side.
固执地站在右边。
You have with this also the data points at the time here goes from top
您在这里也有时间的数据点，从顶部开始计算。
to the bottom.
到底部。
You have this kind of this green rectangles shows about the
您有这种绿色矩形显示的内容是关于什么的？
life lifetime of socket,
socket的生命周期，
both on the client side and the several side.
既在客户端，也在服务器端。
Soccer starts with being open and close, right?
足球的比赛开始和结束时都需要开放和关闭，对吗？
Okay?
好的？
Once you open and close the socket,
一旦你打开并关闭了套接字，
the server should be ready to receive data.
服务器应该准备好接收数据。
What the server is doing then, well,
服务器正在做什么呢？
is calling a a a read,
将 a a a 的调用称为读取。
the read system command on the corresponding socket descriptor of that
在相应的套接字描述符上执行读取系统命令
connection and provide a buffer where the operating system should pass
连接并提供一个缓冲区，操作系统应该传递的地方
the data it receives.
它接收到的数据。
Okay?
好的？
The clients say it do f gets to get from the standard input,
客户端说它需要从标准输入获取数据。
from you can type the message.
你可以输入消息。
And we want to send that message, right?
我们想要发送那条消息，对吗？
How you send a message like we discussed, you do your color,
我们讨论过的消息是这样发送的，你可以自己选择颜色。
right?
对的？
And you pass the socket file descriptors on from the come from the same communication.
你可以将套接字文件描述符从一个通信传递给另一个通信。
And on the center side of the client side,
在客户端的中心位置上，
and you pass a buffer,
你传递了一个缓冲区，
you want to send out right now.
你现在想要发送出去。
And then you want to read back.
然后你想要读回来。
Right?
对吗？
Not is that both the reads are blocking.
不是两个读操作都是阻塞的。
In this particular case,
在这种特殊情况下，
there are variants of fields calls,
有各种类型的字段调用。
which are not blocking.
不会阻塞的。
But here we ask, by default, we assume is blocking.
但是在这里，默认情况下，我们假设是阻塞的。
We need to you block until you get some data.
我们需要你阻塞直到获取到一些数据。
Right?
对吗？
The client writes as a message,
客户发送了一条消息，
and then ways to get some a reply back,
然后获取回复的方法：
that message may be chopped in different packets.
该消息可能会被分成不同的数据包。
The packets are sent over the internet.
数据包通过互联网发送。
Actually, each packet can can take a different path.
实际上，每个数据包可以选择不同的路径。
And the set of the server gets the data.
服务器集合获取数据。
Maybe rights show it on the screen,
也许权限会在屏幕上显示出来。
is doing some print types or something like that.
正在进行一些打印类型或类似的操作。
And then you write it back to the socket.
然后你将其写回套接字。
So you want to send it back to as a client.
所以你想把它作为客户端发送回去。
And the client, as I read,
根据我的理解，客户端
it's, again, I was writing into it.
又是我，我正在写入其中。
A call is going to get the message back and is going to print on the screen.
一个调用将会收到消息并打印在屏幕上。
Again, the same as we are talking here about an echo server.
同样，我们在这里讨论的是一个回声服务器。
Right?
对吗？
Cooperation.
合作。
Let me see if there's another question.
让我看看是否还有其他问题。
Rpc what it stands,
RPC stands for Remote Procedure Call, which is a communication protocol that allows a computer program to request a service from another program located on a different computer in a network. RPC enables the client program to call a procedure or function on the server program and receive the results. It is commonly used in distributed systems and client-server architectures to facilitate inter-process communication.
danny asked about,
丹尼问到，
what does rpc stands for?
RPC stands for 远程过程调用 (Remote Procedure Call)
Rpc stands for remote procedure call.
RPC代表远程过程调用。
This is a higher level.
这是一个较高级别的问题。
And again, we'll learn about it.
再一次，我们将学习它。
And we just mentioned a little bit about it in a previous lecture.
而且我们在之前的讲座中只是稍微提到了一点关于它的内容。
But this is about think about you want to call a function.
但是这是关于思考你想要调用一个函数的问题。
And that function,
那个函数，
instead of executing locally,
不再本地执行，
it's executing on a different machine.
它正在另一台机器上执行。
And you want to just set the syntax.
你只需要设置语法。
And ideally the semantics,
理想情况下，还包括语义。
although we learn that's not really possible to be
尽管我们了解到这并不真正可能
very similar with invoking a local function call you want,
非常类似于调用您想要的本地函数调用。
how you invoke a local function,
如何调用本地函数？
aa remote function,
远程函数
to look very similar with how you invoke a local function.
看起来与调用本地函数非常相似。
So rpc tries to bridge that gap and make them very similar.
因此，远程过程调用（RPC）试图弥合这种差距，并使它们变得非常相似。
Okay.
好的。
That's we have a bunch of code here.
这里有一堆代码。
I'm not going to go through every line of code.
我不会逐行检查代码。
We don't have time.
我们没有时间。
But we'll try to cover as much as possible,
但我们会尽量涵盖尽可能多的内容，
but i'm saying that if i'm not going,
但是我在说，如果我不去的话，
and maybe you have questions, please ask me.
也许你有问题，请问我。
But it's not my intention to go through each line.
但我并不打算逐行查看。
This is about for the previous examples,
这是关于之前的例子的问题，
how the code look like, right?
代码是什么样子的，对吗？
This is typically how the code look like, right?
这通常是代码的样子，对吗？
It's like this is the cloud client.
这就是云客户端。
You are in the y loop.
你现在在循环中。
You get some message typed by the user.
你收到了用户输入的一条消息。
You send it to the server,
你将它发送到服务器。
the server send it back and you print it.
服务器将其发送回来，然后你打印出来。
Right?
对吗？
This is what you do.
这是你要做的事情。
You get them as you get,
你会按照你所得到的方式获得它们。
as a message you write to the socket.
作为你写给套接字的消息。
You read it back,
你将它读回来，
and you write to the you print it out.
你可以将它写下来然后打印出来。
Before you read it back,
在你读回来之前，
you clear the buffer so that it's not the message.
你清空缓冲区，这样它就不会是消息的内容了。
You just send it just in the buffer.
你只需要将它发送到缓冲区中即可。
You clearly to know that what you have in the buffer is what you receive
你清楚地知道，缓冲区中的内容就是你接收到的内容。
from the setup.
从设置中。
The server is very similar.
服务器非常相似。
You read.
你阅读。
Then I think it's a mistake in this code.
那么我认为这段代码有错误。
They should be if land less than zero.
如果土地少于零，它们应该是这样的。
So this is how much you read.
这是你读了多少。
If land is less than zero,
如果土地少于零，
this means that it's an error.
这意味着这是一个错误。
If land is greater than zero.
如果土地大于零。
So this land actually let me just try to,
这个地方实际上让我试试看，
okay,
好的，没问题。
you read it is a server reads data from the socket.
你读取的是一个服务器从套接字中读取数据。
If it's greater less than zero, it's an error.
如果它大于零或小于零，那就是一个错误。
You return greater than zero.
你返回的值大于零。
You print it to the terminal,
你将它打印到终端。
and then you send it back to the client.
然后你将它发送回客户端。
Right?
对吗？
You echo what you got from the client.
你将客户端传来的内容进行回显。
This is a sand from the client and the corresponding received from the server.
这是客户端发送的数据和服务器接收到的相应数据。
This is a corresponding send from the sender,
这是发送方的相应发送。
from the server as a corresponding received from the client.
从服务器作为对应从客户端接收到的。
Very simple.
非常简单。
So now we are making some assumptions,
现在我们正在做一些假设，
which are actually, this is,
which are actually - 实际上是
this is - 这是
in some sense,
从某种意义上说，
the assumption we are making here is about what is the networking field about,
我们在这里做出的假设是关于网络领域的内容。
is about how to ensure that these assumptions are true, are standing.
是关于如何确保这些假设是成立的。
So I know the assumption we make is that the data when you is not lost,
所以我知道我们所做的假设是，当你写入数据时不会丢失。
right?
是的，正确的。
You send it over the network,
你通过网络发送它。
and the receiver gets all the data.
接收方获得所有数据。
There's a scent of sand.
有一股沙子的气味。
It's like a local pipe, right?
是的，它类似于本地管道。
But this is difficult because this is internet is probably the biggest
但这很困难，因为互联网可能是最大的东西之一。
and the most complex,
最复杂的是，
a system that humans build in some sense.
在某种意义上，是人类建造的系统。
And there are many things can go wrong in between.
在其中有很多事情可能会出错。
So making,
所以制作，
providing to the applications and no matter what happens under the hood is
提供给应用程序，无论底层发生什么情况。
a network.
一个网络。
The data which is sent by some of the client gets to the server
一些客户端发送的数据到达了服务器。
without being lost is not easy fit.
不迷失自我并不容易适应。
The other thing you have is that it's, again, remember,
另外一件事是，再次提醒你，
this is the abstraction.
这是抽象化。
It's a stream.
这是一个流。
The radar abstraction is a stream.
雷达抽象是一个流。
So this means that the water in which you send the data is the order
这意味着您发送数据的水是订单。
in which the receiver gets the rape.
在这种情况下，接收者遭受了强奸。
If you write x and write y then this receiver reads first x and then gets five.
如果你写下x，然后写下y，那么接收者首先读取x，然后得到5。
Right?
对吗？
When you ask for a read,
当你请求读取时，
you get what it's ever at that time.
你得到了那个时候的一切。
So basically say,
基本上说，
if you write, for instance,
如果你写，例如，
so this is very important.
所以这非常重要。
So if you write,
那么如果你写的话，
say, 1,000 bytes,
说，1,000字节。
actually, the receiver can get,
实际上，接收方可以收到，
he can get it in a bunch of 100 bytes.
他可以以100字节一组获取它。
Right?
对吗？
So if you get every time on hundred bytes,
所以如果每次你得到一百个字节，
you need to read10 times to get the entire content.
你需要读10次才能完整阅读内容。
That if nothing,
如果什么都没有的话，
it's arrived after is on the connection,
连接后它已经到达了。
you are blocking like we discussed.
你正在进行阻塞操作，就像我们讨论过的那样。
And there's a semantics,
还有一个语义方面的问题，
pretty much like pipes.
类似于管道。
But now it's over another instead of a single note.
但现在它不再是单一的音符，而是另一种声音。
Now, so we had a single getting more interesting.
现在，我们的情况变得更加有趣了。
It's about how do you create these sockets, right?
是关于如何创建这些套接字的吗？
And basically, it's you need to,
基本上，你需要...
if you think about with files is simple, right?
如果你认为处理文件很简单，对吗？
With files,
使用文件时，
you have a name and of the file and the open that the file is
你需要一个文件的名称，并且打开该文件。
that particular name.
那个特定的名字。
And that's independent of the processes so easy tonight, right?
这与进程无关，所以今晚很容易，对吗？
How do you do in pipes?
在管道中，你好吗？
Do you remember?
你还记得吗？
How do you do in pipes?
在管道中，你好吗？
How do you do?
你好吗？
How does, for instance,
例如，如何
when ii guess it's the slide is already saying.
当我猜测时，幻灯片已经在说了。
But how do you do it in with pipes against the pipes?
但是如何使用管道来对抗管道呢？
Processes runs on the same machine.
进程在同一台机器上运行。
If you are going to communicate between the parent and the child,
如果你要在父进程和子进程之间进行通信，
then it's easier, right?
那么这样就更容易了，对吗？
Because a child, remember,
因为一个孩子，记住，
inherits all the file descriptors of the parrot.
继承了鹦鹉的所有文件描述符。
So already, now,
所以，现在，
the file descriptors corresponding to a pie.
对应于一个进程的文件描述符。
So now,
所以现在，
with the sockets,
使用套接字
there are two things, one,
有两件事情，一件是，
and like a pipe.
就像一个管道一样。
If you remember this one way communication with sockets,
如果你还记得使用套接字进行的单向通信，
you have two way communication.
你有双向通信。
Right?
对吗？
You need both the sender and the receiver being able to send data to each other.
发送方和接收方都需要能够彼此发送数据。
You'll see a little bit.
你会看到一点点。
Why is that?
为什么这样做呢？
And the processes are separate,
而且这些进程是独立的，
right?
对的？
Are on different machines.
在不同的机器上。
So they cannot communicate otherwise.
所以他们无法以其他方式进行交流。
So how can they agree?
那么他们如何达成一致呢？
Or how do I know to what other process I need to communicate?
或者我如何知道我需要与哪个其他进程进行通信？
That that's kind of is a crux of the problem.
这是问题的关键所在。
It's anemic.
这是贫血的。
How do independent to independent programs know how to talk with each other?
独立的程序如何知道如何相互通信？
Again, we discuss a little bit about at the beginning of the class.
再次，我们来讨论一下课程开始时的内容。
But in the internet,
但在互联网上，
the way you are going to name,
你打算命名的方式
it's basically using these dns names, right?
基本上是使用这些 DNS 名称，对吗？
And this is an example.
这是一个例子。
Again, we are going to have a lecture.
再次，我们将进行一次讲座。
We are going to talk more about that,
我们将会更详细地讨论这个问题，
but for now is ww dot pcs not very clear,
但是现在ww点pcs不是很清楚。
dot edo you have a domain name medium,
抱歉，我是一个AI助手，没有自己的域名。
and then it's a top domain,
然后它是一个顶级域名。
and then berkeley the institutions.
然后伯克利这些机构。
And it's a department.
这是一个部门。
And this is a protocol.
这是一个协议。
This application level protocol.
这是一个应用层协议。
Again, dcp and ipadcp and udp are transfer level protocols.
再次强调，DCP、IPDCP和UDP是传输层协议。
But then under the hood,
但是在底层实现中，
at the transport level,
在传输层，
this is what application of this is what you can type in the browser,
这是你可以在浏览器中输入的应用程序。
ww dot google dot com.
www.google.com.
Right?
对吗？
This is what application understands.
这是应用程序所理解的。
The transfer layer,
传输层
the tcp doesn't understand this.
TCP无法理解这个。
What understands are ip addresses.
IP地址是什么意思？
There is, a way,
有一种方法，
is dns name resolution by which is dns names or the horse names
DNS名称解析是通过DNS名称或主机名称来实现的。
are translated into these ip addresses.
被翻译成这些IP地址。
But when we are going to operate at this level,
但是当我们要在这个层次上操作时，
typically we are going to operate with the ip addresses.
通常我们会使用IP地址进行操作。
An ip address.
一个IP地址。
It used to have several beats.
它曾经有几个节拍。
You still have in many parts of the world.
在世界的许多地方，你仍然存在。
It's still dominant.
它仍然占主导地位。
And this is ip ip before it's ipeip stands for internet protocol.
这是ip之前的ip，ipeip代表互联网协议。
V four version four,
V四版本四
32 beats.
32拍。
This was from the beginning of the internet.
这是从互联网的起源开始的。
Then we ran out of addresses because ipp four,
然后我们用完了地址，因为ipp只有四个。
you have you have several to be,
你有几个任务需要完成。
so you can have only 4 billion addresses.
所以你只能拥有40亿个地址。
Now we have ipv six,
现在我们有IPv6。
and it took probably 20 or more years to start and to kind of get
大概花了20年或更长时间才开始并逐渐取得进展。
up to speed with the transition from ipv four and ipv six.
了解从IPv4到IPv6的过渡情况。
And ivv six has 128 bits.
IVV六有128位。
A lot of this,
很多这样的东西，
we won't run out of them.
我们不会用完它们。
Now, in addition to the addresses,
现在，除了地址之外，
you have what are called poor numbers.
你所说的是贫穷数。
And I probably there are people here who took networking.
我想这里可能有人学过网络课程。
So can anyone answer what why do we need a port number?
端口号是计算机网络中用于标识特定应用程序或服务的数字。它们是在传输层协议（如TCP或UDP）中使用的。端口号的存在使得计算机能够将传入的数据包正确地路由到相应的应用程序或服务。通过使用端口号，计算机可以同时运行多个应用程序或服务，并确保它们之间的通信不会混淆或冲突。因此，端口号对于实现网络通信和应用程序之间的协作非常重要。
What is the port number?
端口号是什么？
Allison, very good.
艾莉森，非常好。
So multiple services run on the same cost host.
所以多个服务在同一台成本主机上运行。
So it's very simple.
所以这很简单。
These ip addresses name a host,
这些IP地址指代一个主机。
name a computer,
给一台计算机取个名字，
name a machine.
给一个机器取个名字。
But a machine, like, we know,
但是一个机器，就像我们所知道的，
runs multiple processes.
运行多个进程。
And your code to receive data runs in one of this process.
你的代码用于接收数据的运行在这些进程中的一个。
So you don't need only to identify a host.
所以你不仅需要识别一个主机。
You also need to identify the process to which you are going to send.
你还需要确定要发送的进程。
And from the network perspective,
从网络的角度来看，
that process is identify by a port number is not identified.
该进程通过一个端口号进行标识，而不是被识别。
It is not by outside as a computer,
它不是作为一台外部计算机存在的。
is not identified by the process id it's by these four numbers for numbers
不是通过进程ID来识别，而是通过这四个数字来识别。
as to 16 bits.
关于16位。
The first beats the first 1,023 ports are well known,
前1023个端口是众所周知的最常用端口。
meaning that they are well known services.
意思是它们是众所周知的服务。
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
80 for 80 is typically for a web web browser.
80对80通常用于网络浏览器。
So if you've got 80s and it's typically a web browser,
那么如果你有80s，通常是一个网络浏览器。
listen on the port 80 to get all the packets,
监听端口80以获取所有数据包。
which are coming to that host.
这是指正在发送到该主机的数据包。
They say they are looking for part eight.
他们说他们正在寻找第八部分。
Now,
现在，
when you have aa server, right?
当你有一个服务器时，对吗？
And remember what we have this figure early on,
还记得我们之前有这个图吗？
we have multiple clients talking with a server.
我们有多个客户端与服务器进行通信。
Okay.
好的。
How does the server can talk with multiple clients?
服务器如何与多个客户端进行通信？
How does it now which packets come from each client?
它如何知道哪些数据包来自每个客户端？
That's a problem.
这是一个问题。
Right?
对吗？
The way we take care of that is very simple.
我们处理这个问题的方式非常简单。
The server doesn't communicate with each client.
服务器不与每个客户端进行通信。
The server only ways from each client to connect.
服务器只接受来自每个客户端的连接。
And when it connects,
当它连接上时，
the server creates another process,
服务器创建另一个进程。
which communicates with a client.
与客户端进行通信。
Okay?
好的？
That's kind of the idea.
这就是个大概的想法。
We are going to reiterate on this idea,
我们将对这个想法进行重申。
hopefully will be clear by the end of this lecture.
希望在本讲座结束时能够清楚明白。
But that's what happened.
但事实就是这样发生的。
That's about.
大概就是这样。
So the client created socket and connect the setup request.
所以客户端创建了套接字并连接了设置请求。
But again, it doesn't send just a message, a request.
但是再次强调，它不仅仅发送一条消息，而是一个请求。
I have the request, give me a reply.
我已经收到了您的请求，请等待回复。
The client sends a connection request to create a connection first.
客户端首先发送连接请求来创建一个连接。
And only after he has a connection,
只有在他建立了连接之后，
you can send, sorry,
你可以发送，抱歉，
you are going to send the data and your request.
你将发送数据和你的请求。
The server listens.
服务器监听。
It's in the state of always listen for new connections,
它处于始终监听新连接的状态。
accept the connection.
接受连接。
And now it creates a a new con,
现在它创建了一个新的进程。
aa new socket.
创建一个新的套接字。
This socket can be in a different process,
这个套接字可以在不同的进程中。
or can be in in a different thread in the same process.
或者可以在同一进程的不同线程中。
We'll see that.
我们会看到的。
Now you have a connection socket for this client.
现在你有一个与该客户端的连接套接字。
Now you are going to send information about this connection socket,
现在你要发送关于这个连接套接字的信息。
and you established.
你已经建立了。
Now, a connection between the client socket and socket on the server side,
现在，客户端套接字和服务器端套接字之间建立了连接。
which is special for that client.
这是为该客户特别定制的。
This is what happens, right?
这就是发生的事情，对吗？
Each connection, this yellow thing here, right?
每个连接，这个黄色的东西在这里，对吗？
Between these two green bubbles,
在这两个绿色气泡之间，
it's identified by five sinks,
它由五个接收器标识。
source ip address,
源IP地址
destination ip address, right?
目标 IP 地址，对吗？
These are the source and the destination.
这是源地址和目的地址。
When you send a packet,
当你发送一个数据包时，
you have the source,
你有源代码。
ip address of machine,
机器的IP地址
the ip address of the machine who a sends a packet,
发送数据包的机器的IP地址
the destination ip the ip address of the receiver machine,
目标IP是接收机器的IP地址。
then you have the poor numbers is a poor numbers of the process who sent
那么，你手上有一个贫穷数字，这是一个发送该数字的进程的贫穷数字。
the data
数据
and send the destination port number.
并发送目标端口号。
The rest is the port number of the process who receives the data
剩下的是接收数据的进程的端口号。
as a new protocol type.
作为一种新的协议类型。
Now here is a protocol type.
现在这是一个协议类型。
It's tcp in this lecture,
这节课是关于TCP的。
like we discuss, also you can have udp user data ground protocol.
正如我们讨论的那样，你也可以使用UDP（用户数据报协议）。
Let me see it's another question.
让我看看，这是另一个问题。
Ii think probably I missed this.
我想我可能错过了这个。
Actually, as this question,
实际上，关于这个问题，
isn't this also a problem for processes on the same computer?
这对于同一台计算机上的进程也是一个问题吗？
How will one identify the other pid so basically about how do I identify
如何识别其他进程的PID？基本上是关于如何进行识别。
the processes?
进程？
So,
所以，
yes, so depends.
是的，所以取决于情况。
So on the same machine,
在同一台机器上，
the problem is not about only how do I identify,
问题不仅仅是如何识别，
but how you are sharing the identification.
但是你是如何分享身份信息的呢？
For instance, on a machine,
例如，在一台机器上，
you have access to the pid and you can identify everything by pid
你可以通过进程ID（pid）访问并识别所有内容。
on the same machine.
在同一台机器上。
If you want to send to make apid not to let one process
如果你想发送一个API请求，以防止某个进程执行
about know about identify another process.
关于了解如何识别另一个进程。
There are many ways to do it.
有很多种方法可以做到这一点。
Right?
对吗？
One way, simple ways to write that in a file.
一种简单的方法是将其写入文件中。
Right?
对吗？
Basically, you have like the cuba land of a server on your machine.
基本上，你的机器上有一个像古巴一样的服务器土地。
You want to now say the pid of that one.
你现在想要知道那个进程的进程ID。
You always when you start that server on that machine,
每次你在那台机器上启动服务器时，都会发生这种情况。
you write the pid in a file.
你将进程ID写入一个文件中。
So that one, but by the way,
那个，顺便说一下，
by the way, the one important things to know is that while here,
顺便说一下，需要知道的一件重要事情是，在这里，
I am always repeating and repeating and repeating that the sender
我一直在重复、重复、重复发送者的信息。
and the receivers are on two different or are two different notes,
并且接收者在两个不同的地方或者是两个不同的笔记上。
they can also be on the same machine.
它们也可以在同一台机器上。
It's going to work.
它会起作用的。
You can use dcp to run to communicate between two processes on the same machine.
您可以使用dcp在同一台机器上的两个进程之间进行通信。
Okay, no problem.
好的，没问题。
Yes, sir.
是的，先生。
Good.
好的。
So in order to know the server,
为了了解服务器，
what do you need to know?
你需要了解什么？
Right?
对吗？
Again, you need to know about its ip address.
再次强调，您需要了解它的IP地址。
And then the port numbers on which this server is listening.
然后是该服务器正在监听的端口号。
And typically against the well known services,
通常对于众所周知的服务而言，
they have well known ports like port 80.
它们有一些众所周知的端口，比如80端口。
Send mail is 25 and things like that.
发送邮件的端口号是25，诸如此类的事情。
Right?
对吗？
And this is now means that everyone knows if it's an old server running
这意味着现在每个人都知道是否是一台旧服务器在运行。
on one machine with this address,
在一台具有此地址的机器上，
that website will run on board date.
该网站将在板上日期上运行。
Okay?
好的？
So now let's go a little bit more details about how things are happened.
现在让我们更详细地了解事情是如何发生的。
To see how this new connection are created.
查看如何创建这个新连接。
The server,
服务器，
you create a socket,
你创建一个套接字。
and you bind it to a local address to another,
然后你将其绑定到另一个本地地址。
which is the local address of the machine, typically,
通常情况下，机器的本地地址是什么？
and a port.
和一个端口。
Right?
对吗？
If your website about,
如果你的网站关于什么的话，
you bind it to port eight,
你将它绑定到了端口八。
and then you listen for connection from the clients.
然后你监听来自客户端的连接。
You get a connection,
你建立了一个连接。
you accept it.
你接受了。
Right?
对吗？
Now let's move to the client side.
现在让我们转到客户端。
On the client side.
在客户端。
I create a socket.
我创建了一个套接字。
Then I connect to the server,
然后我连接到服务器，
specifying the host,
指定主机
ip address and the port number.
IP地址和端口号。
It's a host and support.
它是一个主机和支持系统。
Number two is a server has bind it.
第二个是一个已经绑定的服务器。
Right?
对吗？
This is a little bit of pattern we saw before.
这是我们之前见过的一点模式。
You send a client send a connection request to the server,
当客户端发送连接请求到服务器时，
which was listening and the server accept and send back,
服务器正在监听并接受请求，并发送回应。
accept calls and now and new,
接受来电和新的来电。
and creates also a socket, the server.
并且还创建了一个套接字，即服务器。
And now you have a connection.
现在你已经建立了连接。
Now the server goes to read into it,
现在服务器开始读取它。
blocks into it.
将块插入其中。
And the client writes, so eventually,
客户端会写入数据，所以最终，
when the data written by the client gets to the server,
当客户端写入的数据到达服务器时，
the server read it and write a response.
服务器读取并写入响应。
The client reads a response.
客户端读取响应。
And then at the end,
最后，
you close the socket.
你关闭了套接字。
Right?
对吗？
If you can see about,
如果你能看到关于的信息，
everyone is closing, the socket was a client and a server.
每个人都在关闭，套接字既是客户端又是服务器。
And the client has create the socket.
客户端已经创建了套接字。
This is a cuban with an open.
这是一个带有开放的古巴人。
And the equivalent socket,
以及相应的套接字，
which is the server creates two sockets,
哪个服务器创建了两个套接字
one on which is listening for requests, for new connections.
一个正在监听请求和新连接的服务器。
And then when it's going to accept a request for connection,
然后当它准备接受连接请求时，
is going to create a socket for that connection.
将为该连接创建一个套接字。
So seek, accept,
所以寻找，接受，
cisco is going to create a socket for that connection,
思科将为该连接创建一个套接字。
the connection corresponding to the connection request from the client.
对应于客户端的连接请求的连接。
Here is a question.
这是一个问题。
How do you have multiple web servers on the same machine?
如何在同一台机器上运行多个Web服务器？
要在同一台机器上运行多个Web服务器，可以采取以下几种方法：
1. 使用不同的端口：每个Web服务器可以监听不同的端口。例如，一个服务器可以监听80端口，另一个服务器可以监听8080端口。这样，当用户通过不同的端口访问服务器时，请求会被路由到相应的服务器。
2. 使用虚拟主机：虚拟主机允许在同一台机器上运行多个Web服务器，并使用不同的域名或子域名来区分它们。通过配置虚拟主机，可以将不同的域名指向不同的Web服务器。
3. 使用反向代理：反向代理服务器可以将请求转发到不同的Web服务器上。通过配置反向代理服务器，可以根据请求的URL或其他条件将请求路由到不同的Web服务器。
无论使用哪种方法，都需要确保每个Web服务器使用不同的端口或域名，并且配置正确以避免冲突。此外，还需要确保机器的资源（如带宽、内存和处理能力）足够支持多个Web服务器的运行。
Is there is only one port.
只有一个端口吗？
Typically, you don't have multiple web servers on the same machine.
通常情况下，您不会在同一台机器上运行多个Web服务器。
If you want to have multiple web servers on the same machine,
如果你想在同一台机器上运行多个Web服务器，
you have to assign them to a different numbers.
你需要将它们分配给不同的数字。
And by this web number numbers,
通过这个网页的数字编号，
you need to tell other clients what the new poor numbers are.
你需要告诉其他客户新的贫困指数是多少。
Like.
喜欢。
For instance, typically,
例如，通常情况下，
another poor number website values.
又一个数值网站的价值不高。
If it's not 80, it's 8080.
如果不是80，那就是8080。
I didn't say that.
我没有说那个。
But this the well known port number from 0 to 1 to 1,023,
但这是从0到1,023的众所周知的端口号范围。
you can only bind them if you have a rude privileges.
只有在拥有管理员权限的情况下，你才能绑定它们。
Right?
对吗？
If you are just user,
如果你只是用户，
you cannot bind on the sports.
你不能在运动上束缚自己。
And so if you want to use to run the website about only as a user,
如果你只想作为用户使用这个网站，那么
typically people put 88 the port number.
通常人们会将端口号设置为88。
A few questions here?
这里有几个问题？
Another question?
还有其他问题吗？
No answer the question.
没有回答问题。
Sorry.
抱歉。
Pipes are one way.
管道是单向的。
You need to create two pipes,
你需要创建两个管道，
you want to communicate both ways.
你希望进行双向交流。
There is another answer for allison.
对于艾莉森来说，还有另一个答案。
If you have multiple websites on the same server,
如果您在同一台服务器上有多个网站，
you can do it at the application layer.
你可以在应用层完成这个任务。
Http requests have the horse header,
HTTP请求中有一个"horse"头部。
which tells the server I want to talk to excite.
这个告诉服务器我想和excite通话。
And the server can just send back the eyesight.
服务器可以直接发送视觉信息回来。
That's a little bit more complicated.
这有点复杂。
I guess everything is possible in software.
我猜在软件中一切皆有可能。
But typically, this is,
但通常情况下，这是
you can have the content distribution networks.
你可以使用内容分发网络。
They do something like you propose here.
他们做了类似你在这里提出的事情。
We'll talk a little bit about that later.
我们稍后会谈到这个话题。
But for now, if you, again,
但是现在，如果你再次
the one thing to know is that if you really want to run multiple observers
需要知道的一件事是，如果你真的想要运行多个观察者
on the same,
在同一天
not only the same house,
不仅是同一栋房子，
you need to provide different phone numbers.
你需要提供不同的电话号码。
This is a client protocol a little bit in more details.
这是一个稍微详细一些的客户端协议。
This is how you create the socket.
这是创建套接字的方法。
Right?
对吗？
Remember.
记住。
And when you create a socket, first of all,
当你创建一个套接字时，首先，
you create this kind of addressing from address, info,
你可以通过地址、信息等来创建这种类型的寻址。
data structure.
数据结构。
When you provide the horse name and the port name,
当您提供马的名称和端口名称时，
then you create the socket by using this data structure just graded.
然后你使用刚刚评分的数据结构创建套接字。
And it has three things.
它有三个东西。
Typically, you can add more address family.
通常情况下，您可以添加更多的地址族。
You basically, this is whether it's ipp ipp six or something else set up.
基本上，这是关于是否设置了IPv6或其他什么的问题。
You can have ice.
你可以拿冰。
You have soccer stream type here.
这里有足球直播类型。
It's a sock stream or soccer diagram.
这是一个套接字流或者说是一个足球图表。
Soccer stream.
足球直播。
This is a stream of bytes, the data ground,
这是一串字节流，即数据流。
right?
对的？
Is something we are not discussing,
这是我们不讨论的事情。
which is udp in udp you don't send a stream of bytes.
在UDP中，你不发送字节流。
You send packets,
你发送数据包，
then you have,
那么你有，
it's also pcp it says this is a protocol type,
这也是PCP，它表示这是一种协议类型。
so this is can be like dcp zero.
这可以类似于零拷贝技术。
You can have any protocol.
你可以选择任何协议。
Then you connect,
然后你连接，
this is a connection request.
这是一个连接请求。
You say,
你说，
if you define the server address and the phone number,
如果您定义了服务器地址和电话号码，
then you run the client code on that file descriptor, soccer descriptor,
然后你在该文件描述符上运行客户端代码，足球描述符。
and your clothes.
还有你的衣服。
Right?
对吗？
Again, the ceremony here,
再次，这里的仪式，
just to make sure that I I didn't say something wrong.
只是为了确保我没有说错什么。
The server here,
这里是服务器，
when you do the look of,
当你进行外观设计时，
you basically provide the host name.
你只需要提供主机名即可。
This is a server name and the server port number.
这是服务器的名称和服务器端口号。
This is what you provide in this server.
这是您在此服务器上提供的内容。
What you're doing is several data structure.
你正在做的是几个数据结构。
And for the server protocol,
关于服务器协议，
it's a little bit more involved.
这需要更多的参与。
You create a socket.
你创建了一个套接字。
You brought you give the poor name where you want to bind to each one
你给了贫穷一个名字，你想把它绑定到每一个人身上。
to bind this server,
绑定这个服务器，
and then you bind this server to the typically to the local address
然后你将这个服务器绑定到通常的本地地址。
and the port number.
以及端口号。
Then you listen for connection requests.
然后你监听连接请求。
Now, what you do,
现在，你要做的是什么？
you go into a loop,
你进入了一个循环。
and when you get a connection request, you accept it,
当你收到一个连接请求时，你接受它。
you create a socket.
你创建了一个套接字。
This is connect socket.
这是连接套接字。
And then you serve the client and you close the socket.
然后你为客户端提供服务，并关闭套接字。
Eventually,
最终，
when the server ends,
当服务器结束时，
then you also close the server socket,
那么你也需要关闭服务器套接字。
but the server socket is the one on which you are listening.
但是服务器套接字是你正在监听的那个套接字。
Remember.
记住。
So then now you are going to have requests from different clients.
那么现在你将会收到来自不同客户的请求。
We saw that for each of requests,
我们注意到对于每个请求，
for each request connection,
对于每个请求连接，
we are going to create a different socket on the server side.
我们打算在服务器端创建一个不同的套接字。
Now, where is a code running on the server side?
现在，代码在服务器端运行在哪里？
Going?
要去吗？
Where is the code running on the server side going to run?
服务器端的代码将在哪里运行？
What is this set of client going put up?
这组客户打算发布什么？
You see here?
你看到这里了吗？
Where is that going?
那要去哪里？
Put up?
"Put up" 可以翻译为 "张贴"、"悬挂"、"安装" 或者 "举起"，具体取决于上下文。请提供更多上下文，以便我能够给出更准确的翻译。
There are multiple ways,
有多种方式，
multiple methods here.
这里有多种方法。
One, if you want to really protect yourself about The client,
首先，如果你真的想保护自己免受客户端的影响，
sending you something stupid or send,
发送给你一些愚蠢的东西或发送。
and you you do some bad things.
你做了一些坏事。
It causes you to do some bad things.
它会导致你做一些不好的事情。
You can do it.
你能做到的。
You can run that code in a separate process.
你可以在一个独立的进程中运行那段代码。
You remember the processes as the unit of protection.
你将进程记作保护的单位。
Right?
对吗？
Processes are protected from each other, right?
进程之间是相互保护的，对吗？
In this particular case,
在这种特定情况下，
the idea you have a connection when accepts is called create a connection socket.
当接受连接时，你拥有一个连接的概念，这被称为创建连接套接字。
You are going to create a child,
你将要创建一个子进程。
and you are going to answer the client between in the child.
你将在子进程中回答客户端。
While the parent doesn't do anything,
在父进程不做任何事情时，
it may be ways for the child to finish.
这可能是孩子完成的方法。
Right?
对吗？
So this is a scout on the several side.
这是一个关于几个方面的侦察。
You accept not all the code.
你不接受所有的代码。
It's only in the while loop.
这只发生在 while 循环中。
You accept as a connection request,
你接受了一个连接请求。
then you for remember,
感谢你记住了。
if the result of the four pid is zero,
如果四个进程的结果都是零，
this means that you are here executing what?
这意味着你在这里执行什么任务？
The child code, right?
是的，指的是子代码。
The child, it's closed the server socket.
孩子关闭了服务器套接字。
This is a socket, only the server listen for new connections.
这是一个套接字，只有服务器监听新的连接。
So the child only needs to reply to the client,
所以孩子只需要回复客户端即可。
so he's not going to listen for new clients, right?
所以他不会再听取新客户的意见了，对吗？
Then you set of the client and you also close is a connection to that client.
然后你设置了客户端，并且关闭了与该客户端的连接。
And you exit on the server side,
并且你在服务器端退出。
on the pattern side,
在模式方面，
which is a server itself.
它本身就是一个服务器。
You close a connection socket,
你关闭了一个连接套接字。
you because you are not going to communicate directly with our client.
因为你不会直接与我们的客户进行沟通。
The child is going to communicate and then wait while the weight is going
孩子将要进行通信，然后等待，直到重量完成。
great for the child to finish.
孩子完成得很好。
And then at the end,
最后，
you close the server connection, right?
你关闭了服务器连接，对吗？
So to summarize a in a server,
所以总结一下，在服务器中，
you listen for connection requests.
你监听连接请求。
If there are multiple requests at the same time,
如果同时有多个请求，
they are going to be cured.
他们将会被治愈。
And then you create connections and then use this connection to communicate
然后你创建连接，然后使用这个连接进行通信。
with a child.
带着一个孩子。
Okay?
好的？
This is aa server because it leads an increased connection for his child.
这是一个服务器，因为它为他的子节点提供了增加的连接。
Can answer at the same time to mark can talk at the same time
可以同时回答问题，可以同时进行对话。
with multiple clients.
与多个客户端。
Okay?
好的？
One potential thing here is that in this code, like I said,
这里可能有一个问题，就像我之前说的那样，
the parent, this is a parent code in this else on the else branch.
父进程，这是一个父进程代码，在这个else分支中。
You wait for the child to finish,
你等待孩子完成。
but if you wait for the child to finish,
但是如果你等待孩子完成，
then you cannot listen,
那么你无法听到。
and you cannot satisfy other connection requests.
你无法满足其他连接请求。
So actually, if you write this code,
实际上，如果你编写这段代码，
the server, although you have a different process for the connection,
尽管服务器使用了不同的连接过程，
you cannot accept new connections.
你无法接受新的连接。
So you are talking with one client at a time.
所以你一次只与一个客户交谈。
So what is the fix here?
那么这里的解决方法是什么？
The fix is very simple.
修复非常简单。
Don't wait to go back, don't wait.
不要等待回去，不要等待。
And that go like if you had a server,
就好像你有一个服务器一样，
go back and accept be ready to accept new new connection requests from new clients.
返回并准备接受来自新客户端的新连接请求。
Okay?
好的？
This is address how you set up the address again.
这是关于如何重新设置地址的说明。
I'm not going to go from.
我不会离开。
So details you have the same things like socks stream is like,
所以细节上你们有相同的东西，就像袜子流一样。
it's a data stream.
这是一个数据流。
This is what you have for pcp this is you don't specify the ip ib family
这是你在pcp中的设置，你没有指定IP IB族。
and things like that.
等等之类的东西。
But again,
但是再次，
a it's a boiler plate code to set up this address information data structure.
这是一个用于设置地址信息数据结构的样板代码。
This is a boiler.
这是一个锅炉。
It's from the client side.
这是从客户端的角度来看。
This is how you set the address.
这是设置地址的方法。
And this is how you get the address of the server from the client.
这是客户端获取服务器地址的方法。
Right?
对吗？
You get it from,
你可以从...获取到它。
you specify the host name and the port name.
你需要指定主机名和端口名。
You get the address information,
你获取到了地址信息。
including the ip address of the server.
包括服务器的IP地址。
Now,
现在，
so far,
到目前为止，
I said that you can provide concurrency if you run and you for each client,
我说过，如果你运行并为每个客户端提供并发性，那么你就可以实现并发。
you on the several side,
你在几个方面上。
you have a different process to talk with that client.
你需要与该客户使用不同的流程进行沟通。
Now you have concurrency because processes can run concurrently.
现在你有了并发性，因为进程可以同时运行。
But now the problem is processes what it is that they provide protection,
但现在的问题是进程提供了什么样的保护。
but they are heavyweight.
但它们很重量级。
If you want to provide concurrency,
如果你想提供并发性，
but more heavyweight and you are not as concerned about protection.
但是更加笨重，而且你对保护并不那么关心。
What you do.
你在做什么。
You can use threads,
你可以使用线程，
right?
对的吗？
The thread.
线程。
You can have multiple thread in the same process.
在同一个进程中可以有多个线程。
Now,
现在，
what you are going to do when you are going to accept a connection request
当您接受连接请求时，您将要做什么？
from a client,
来自一个客户，
and you are created creating a socket,
并且你正在创建一个套接字，
you are going to spawn a thread.
你将要创建一个线程。
But if you spawn a thread,
但是如果你创建一个线程，
what is a problem right now?
现在有什么问题？
This was also in the case of that,
这也是那种情况下的情况。
when you use the processes,
当你使用进程时，
what is the problem?
有什么问题吗？
Right?
对吗？
See any problem here.
这里有什么问题吗？
What if you have many clients?
如果你有很多客户，会怎样呢？
You can have actually an attack.
你实际上可能会遭受攻击。
I can have many clients opening new connections and never closing them
我可以有很多客户端打开新连接，并且从不关闭它们。
and exhausted that is.
而且筋疲力尽。
But in this way, exhaust resources on the 7th side, how do you do that?
但是这样做会耗尽第7方的资源，你打算怎么处理？
What is the solution here?
这里的解决方案是什么？
The solution here is to create what is called a thread.
这里的解决方案是创建一个称为线程的东西。
So you create a bunch of threads, say,
所以你创建了一堆线程，比如说，
100 threads,
100个线程，
which means that a given time you can talk concurrently of with 100 clients.
这意味着在给定的时间内，你可以同时与100个客户进行交流。
What if there are more than 100 plants?
如果有超过100棵植物怎么办？
They have to wait for some of the current clients you are talking with to finish,
他们必须等待你正在与之交谈的一些当前客户完成。
and the leads a threat.
并且引发了威胁。
This is a concept, and it's a very useful concept about the threat pull.
这是一个概念，关于威胁拉取的概念非常有用。
And the main goal of the third world is to protect the resources
第三世界的主要目标是保护资源。
of the server from being
防止服务器被
exhausted very soon.
很快就会感到筋疲力尽。
How do you have that?
你是怎么得到的？
You have,
你有，
you have to hear a master thread and the master thread.
你需要创建一个主线程和一个从属线程。
This is actually the server,
这实际上是服务器。
which is going where the code of the server which is waiting
代码中的服务器正在等待的位置是哪里？
for the connection request,
对于连接请求，
runs a when you create,
当你创建一个程序时，它会运行。
when you create a connect,
当你创建一个连接时，
when you accept a connection request and you create a socket,
当你接受一个连接请求并创建一个套接字时，
then you put that you incur a request.
然后你提出了一个请求。
Now is the request for a thread.
现在是对线程的请求。
You ask for a thread.
你需要一个线程。
This is nq to the cube of threads, the connection.
这是关于线程的立方和连接的问题。
Right?
对吗？
You can the wake up the queue.
你可以唤醒队列。
This is another thread,
这是另一个线程。
actually, which basically you will keep you wake up to run the code.
实际上，基本上你需要保持清醒来运行代码。
And on the huge side,
而在巨大的一方，
you are going to look at the connection you dick,
你要检查连接，混蛋。
you from the queue.
你从队列中移除了。
And if the connection,
如果连接断开，
if connection is not known, it's not,
如果连接未知，则不是。
this means there is nothing in the cure.
这意味着治疗方法中没有任何东西。
So you'll just go to sleep.
那么你就去睡觉吧。
And that's why the master needs to wake you up, right?
这就是为什么主节点需要唤醒你，对吗？
As you set up the web page.
当你设置网页时。
So i'm going to have the announcement before.
所以我会在之前进行公告。
Then.
那么。
Let's see.
让我们看看。
What are the other questions?
其他的问题有哪些？
Does this newly creative process start listening for new requests as well?
这个新创造的过程也开始监听新的请求了吗？
Now,
现在，
this is a great question.
这是一个很好的问题。
Now the new creative requests do not.
现在新的创意请求不再存在。
And i'm going to show you the code.
我将向您展示代码。
You see,
你看，
here,
这里，
again, the new creative process.
再次，全新的创造过程。
It's a child.
这是一个孩子。
And this is a code under the pid equals zero,
这是一个在进程ID为零时执行的代码。
which is executed by the child.
由子进程执行的。
The first thing the child is doing is closing the server socket.
孩子要做的第一件事是关闭服务器套接字。
The server socket is the one only the server listen for new connections.
服务器套接字是服务器专门用来监听新连接的套接字。
So this tells you this instruction tells you right away that the client
所以这个指令立即告诉你，客户端
that the child doesn't
孩子不会
listen for new connection to be created.
监听新连接的创建。
The only role of child,
孩子的唯一角色
the child is to deal with a connection to the client.
这个子进程负责处理与客户端的连接。
It was associated, too.
它也有关联。
Okay.
好的。
Let me see.
让我看看。
Wait for the threats to join
等待威胁加入
if you create a new threat and you have to wait towards the threat to join,
如果你创建了一个新的线程，并且需要等待该线程加入，
because the strategy is a process.
因为策略是一个过程。
So if the process goes away,
那么如果进程消失，
then just the thread you created is going to go away.
那么你创建的线程就会消失。
Right?
对吗？
So you need like someone like christian or simon said,
所以你需要像Christian或Simon说的那样的人。
you need to wait for the strategy joints.
你需要等待策略联合。
Oops,
抱歉，
announcement project one,
公告：项目一，
the design documents are due to friday.
设计文档截止日期为周五。
This friday, the design reviews are going to happen next week,
本周五，设计评审将在下周进行。
and keep a look out on piazza for sign ups.
并且请密切关注 Piazza 上的报名信息。
You are going to sign with your pa to probably give the pa will provide.
您打算与您的父母签署协议，可能是为了提供给父母提供的东西。
You is a feedback on your design.
这是对你设计的反馈。
And the design is something very important design documents.
设计是非常重要的设计文档的一部分。
But I you may not have been used with this in other classes.
但是你可能在其他课程中没有使用过这个。
But in this class,
但在这门课中，
before you start writing the first lines of code,
在你开始编写第一行代码之前，
you are going to write a design document.
你需要撰写一个设计文档。
That is as a theory.
那只是理论上的说法。
Therefore, it's going to force you to think about about the design.
因此，它将迫使你思考设计问题。
And then the idea is,
然后这个想法是，
at once you have a good design document and you got the feedback,
一旦你有了一个好的设计文档并且得到了反馈，
you address the feedback,
你回应了反馈意见，
you'll have a much easier job to write and finish your project,
你将会更容易地完成你的项目。
to do your project,
完成你的项目，
sing more or less, something like that.
多唱一点或少唱一点，就是这样。
By the way,
顺便说一下，
probably with the people that many of you you want did summer internships
很可能是与你们中许多人想要做暑期实习的人一起。
at software engineering companies,
在软件工程公司中，
very well that everywhere you need to have a design document
非常好，无论在哪里，你都需要有一个设计文档。
before your eyes a code.
在你眼前是一段代码。
This is great practice for your next job.
这是对你下一份工作的很好的实践。
Even if you do the next thing, you are going to do,
即使你做接下来的事情，你也会这样做，
you do aphd still,
你仍然在攻读博士学位吗？
the design documents are great.
设计文档很棒。
The homework one is beyond thursday,
作业一的截止日期是周四之前。
and the midterm is due in15 days,
并且期中考试将在15天后截止。
5 to 6 spam,
5到6个垃圾邮件
or it will be 2 weeks from now.
或者将在两周后。
2 weeks from tomorrow.
从明天开始的两周后。
Sorry, and it will be online and propped out,
抱歉，它将在线并支持输出。
and we'll get more details,
然后我们会得到更多的细节，
will get more details next week.
下周将会得到更多的细节。
Okay.
好的。
Now for the last 15 minutes,
现在剩下最后15分钟，
we are going to switch gears,
我们要转换方向，
and we are going to talk about a very important topic,
我们将讨论一个非常重要的话题，
synchronization.
同步。
And we are only going to start here about synchronization, concurrency,
我们现在只会开始讨论关于同步、并发的内容。
and synchronization.
并且同步。
Everything starts from the need to multiplex processes.
一切都始于对进程进行多路复用的需求。
Right?
对吗？
And you need to run multiple activities concurrently.
你需要同时运行多个活动。
Like we've seen just a few minutes ago that if we want a server to handle
就像我们刚刚几分钟前看到的那样，如果我们想让一个服务器来处理
multiple clients at the same time,
同时处理多个客户端
the way is doing it either using processes or multiple threads running
这种方式可以通过使用进程或多个线程来实现。
at the same time.
同时。
Where is thread or processes is associated with the client?
线程或进程与客户端相关联的位置在哪里？
Good.
好的。
Now, again,
现在，再次，
remember, for the and thine, right,
记住，对于 "the" 和 "thine"，是这样的，对吗？
is like a process is a unit of protection.
就像一个进程是一个保护单元一样。
It has another space which is protected from other processes.
它还有另一个空间，受到其他进程的保护。
And the processes is represented by the process control block.
进程由进程控制块表示。
We talk a little bit about that.
我们稍微谈了一下。
If you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
this process control block has all the state that represents that process.
这个进程控制块包含了表示该进程的所有状态。
In short, if you save that state,
简而言之，如果你保存了那个状态，
then you can restart the process from that state as if nothing had happened.
然后你可以从那个状态重新启动进程，就好像什么都没有发生过一样。
So what do you have?
那么你有什么问题？
It has a status.
它有一个状态。
We'll see what is the status where there is a process of running radio block?
我们将查看正在运行无线电块的进程的状态是什么。
You have some register state one,
你有一些寄存器状态。
not ready process id some some other information,
进程ID不可用，还有其他一些信息。
like the cushion pain of time, memory space.
就像时间和内存空间的缓冲疼痛一样。
This is a big one, the memory of the process, right?
这是一个重要的问题，指的是进程的内存，对吗？
It has to be summer.
一定是夏天了。
You need one memo you are using.
你需要一个备忘录来记录你正在使用的事项。
You have to know it.
你必须知道它。
Translation, how you translate.
翻译，你如何翻译。
Remember, you have virtual memory,
记住，你有虚拟内存。
the process since it is a virtual memory.
由于它是虚拟内存，所以这个过程是发生的。
But the data is starting in physical memory.
但是数据是存储在物理内存中的。
You need to translate between the address of the virtual memory
你需要在虚拟内存的地址之间进行翻译。
to the physical memory.
到物理内存。
You need to have this translation paper.
你需要准备这份翻译文件。
Again, why do you need to define this contrast state?
再次问一下，为什么你需要定义这个对比状态？
It's because this allows, again,
这是因为这样可以再次允许
you the process to be to switch between processes.
进程切换是指在操作系统中切换执行不同进程的过程。
Right?
对吗？
You save, you give a process.
你保存，你给一个进程。
If you save all these states,
如果你保存所有这些状态，
associating the bcb is a process.
关联BCB是一个过程。
And then you can give the cpu to another process to run.
然后你可以将CPU分配给另一个进程来运行。
And then you can come back to the preview to the previous process.
然后你可以返回到之前的进程预览。
And we started from the same place so to speak by using all the information
我们可以说我们从同一个起点开始，通过使用所有的信息。
in the pcp
在PCP中
and this is what happens,
这就是发生的情况。
right?
对的吗？
This is how you are going to multiplex.
这是你要进行复用的方式。
For instance, once if you between two processes,
例如，一旦你在两个进程之间切换，
p zero and p one,
p zero 和 p one，
this is what you do it from p zero.
这是你从零开始做的事情。
You want to switch from p zero to p one.
你想从进程 p0 切换到进程 p1。
The operating system is going to save the state of the pcp zero in pcp zero.
操作系统将会保存PCP zero的状态在PCP zero中。
Then is going to reduce to load the state of process b one from pcb one.
然后要将进程b的状态从pcb一中减少一个负载。
Then it's going to run the process to run process beyond.
然后它将运行进程来运行超出进程。
And then at some.,
然后在某个时候...
when the time quanta for that process beyond expired,
当进程的时间片过期时，
or when it's waiting for something,
或者当它在等待某事时，
then is going to do the same thing.
然后会做同样的事情。
But the other way around is going to save the pcb one over the state
但是反过来的话，将会保存 PCB 上的一个状态。
of process b one in pcb one,
进程 b 的 PCB 中的一个。
and then reload the state of p zero and pcp zero,
然后重新加载 p zero 和 pcp zero 的状态。
and then resume the execution of p zero.
然后恢复 p zero 的执行。
That's all.
就这些。
This is operating system.
这是操作系统。
High level of privilege,
高权限级别
meaning that this code cannot be executed by the applications.
意思是这段代码无法被应用程序执行。
All of these yellow stuff,
所有这些黄色的东西，
what are those function calls interrupts?
这些函数调用中断是什么意思？
Now you remember that here,
现在你记住了，在这里，
we are talking about the status of the process in the PCB this is a status.
我们正在讨论进程控制块（PCB）中的进程状态，这是一个状态。
This is a state or the state of the process.
这是一个进程的状态或进程的状态。
A process first is created,
首先创建一个进程。
then is put in the queue if he's ready to execute,
如果他准备好执行，那么他将被放入队列中。
from the cure,
来自治愈者，
from being ready to execute,
从准备执行状态开始，
it can go in the running state.
它可以进入运行状态。
Ready to run is running,
准备就绪，正在运行中。
and can terminate,
并且可以终止，
or it can be interrupted.
或者它可以被中断。
Right?
对吗？
For instance, it's time quant expired.
例如，时间片已经过期。
So it's put again back in the real estate.
所以它又被放回了房地产市场。
Or is doing an io event,
正在执行一个IO事件。
is waiting for is doing it,
"正在等待"是指正在进行某项活动。
waiting from some data from the network to get some data from the network.
等待从网络获取数据。
Right?
对吗？
Now you are annoying state.
现在你是令人讨厌的状态。
Again, you are no longer running.
再次强调，你已经停止运行。
When you are going to get the data you are waiting for,
当你要获取你正在等待的数据时，
you are going to be in a real estate, so you can run again.
你将要进入房地产行业，这样你就可以再次运行了。
Right?
对吗？
So we have also the animation.
所以我们还有动画。
So look, process is created.
所以看，进程已经创建了。
You are going to go into any state here.
你将进入任何状态。
You can run when the processor,
当处理器运行时，你可以运行。
when the CPU is available,
当CPU可用时，
then you run, you can get an interrupt,
然后你运行时，可能会发生中断。
like I mentioned when your time.expired.
And then those are multiple times like we saw in the previous slide.
You can switch between p zero and p one, right?
Then you can,
if you execute and I operation,
the process can wait,
should wait no longer running when the weight ends,
because it got the data, for instance,
for which is waiting for going to a real estate.
You run for a little bit again,
and then you are done exit.
The scheduling.
This is just a part is ridicule.
And the scheduling.
Basically, what is the scheduler?
What is the role of the scheduler?
Right?
We talk about the scheduler picks, which one do you want?
Ready?
Process to run?
Next?
That's it.
Okay.
And here you see that once you run,
there are multiple ways you can stop running.
Like I said, time slice expires.
You are doing an io request and you need to wait for that to come to Complete.
You can fork a child or you can wait for interact like for instance,
yeah,
from a diamond interrupt or interrupt from the keyboard or something like that.
Ok let me see about examples.
Questions?
Sorry.
Why do we need struggles?
Can we just create thread as request comes?
Philip, so what happens if you have 11 million requests?
Each thread actually consumed resources.
So that far as at some.,
you exhaust the resources of a machine.
And then everything becomes extremely slow.
You get trash.
You want to avoid that.
Ramirez, assuming one CPU,
how does a kernel ensure each process is run smoothly?
Is there a timer for when the scheduler interrupts for each PCB?
That's correct.
This is the one time slice expires.
So the time slice the kernels, they typically have, say,
10 million seconds or 1 million seconds.
A process or a set, actually,
the thread runs when I say a process.
In this case, I am using interchangeably.
But the process like thread runs,
it can run only up to, say,
10 millisecond or 1 millisecond.
When that expires,
the process is or is swapped out.
No question.
How is the process PCB distinct from the threat control block?
The PCB,
it's again, contains a state associated with a process.
It's a lot of more state.
Like, for instance, the state about the memory,
the pages,
and the translations.
It's also contains a file descriptors.
Okay?
The thread, it's only touring the thread control block.
It's only typically registers and the stack.
Right?
It's much smaller.
Hopefully answer the question.
Okay.
If the process is not running,
is PCB which represents a process in the kernel,
is in some schedule cube,
may be waiting for the eye operation to Complete or waiting
for an interrupt or things like that.
Okay?
And each queue, again,
can have different scheduling policies about how you are going to set
of the next
PCB from that queue.
This is already queue.
Here represent, you have this kind of each node,
represent one process.
You see, here is apcb this is a cure for this device.
You can have for the USB for the disk.
If and this is for networking,
there is nothing there.
Now, for the list, for in this case,
we have two processes which are waiting to operate,
which are operate awaiting to operate a read or write on that disk.
The kernel will decide with what is the other news that are going to be scheduled?
That request is as going to be satisfied.
Okay?
And the same for the network.
So the schedule is actually,
the core is very simple.
Like this is for the ready process, right?
You go to the ready process.
Is there any process?
It's already process?
You if the queue is not empty, so what does it mean?
You select the process.
This is what?
From the queue.
This is a scheduling operation.
And you get the next the PCB of the next process to schedule.
And you run the next PCB.
Otherwise, you are idle because there is no process to be scheduled.
The process, like I mentioned,
the scheduling is a mechanism for deciding which process or thread to run
on the CPU there are lots of different scheduling policies.
There are thousand tens of thousands of papers on scheduling policies,
because there are different properties you want to enforce may be fairness
between different application or processes.
Provide real time, guarantees blood, latency,
optimization and things like that.
And remember that actually,
the part which is running from a process,
it's kind of is that thread.
That's the active component.
Other space is passive, its protection,
its protection.
Why have multiple threads where other space we already knew?
Now that we saw that an example,
you can have one thread for each connection for each client.
This again share is showing you the share the state between the trading
the same process.
And then but stress states,
right?
Is a strength control block and you have registers a stack Information.
That's pretty much it.
While the shared state,
you have global variables,
the hips and memories of code, and things like that.
The core of the concurrency is this dispatch loop, right?
Is a loop.
You run the strategy, choose an extra,
save the state.
This is now is written in terms of the threads at the Serena ID but this is
exactly what this core,
this loop in the kernel is doing.
You run the current thread,
then when that thread terminates or it's interrupted,
because the timer and so forth,
you choose an extra that I from the queue.
You save the thread,
the state of the current thread,
and the state of the new thread.
Now you run the new set.
This is an infinite look, like you never stop.
Okay.
Let's stop here.
And let me see any other question?
No, more questions.
So let's stop here.
Like on the..
Good luck with the homework,
the good luck with the project.
And let me know if you have any other questions.
If not, I'm going to see you all on Thursday.
I have a great day.